So imagine you are a software engineer and,
you are maintaining a code base, and you developed a new context.
I don't know, a Claude Code skill, for example.
How do you know if it's effective?
How do you test it?
So, yeah, I'm.
I, research engineer at Tessl.
And I'm building, evaluation platform for agents.
What it means is, basically, we want to allow to
evaluate the performance of any agents, of any model
in different code bases, in any code base, basically with any context,
make it an appropriate, proprietary code base or open source code base,
making it evolves, available for anyone so that you can build, benchmarks.
And my talk will be about
the main concepts, like the main building blocks of such platform,
in case you want to develop something like this yourself.
Or reuse some of those blocks.
And why, why it's art.
And what are the main challenges?
And so on specifically, we'll cover like in three things.
First of all, why vaults matter today?
Because it's a very hot topic.
Every Frontier Labs talk is,
evolves second again, like, what are the core concepts?
What are the main building blocks?
And third, how we approach these tasks now, because you're such a platform
and how can you use it, and integrate in your code base if you're interested.
Cool.
But before we dive into specifics, I want to make sure that we are all
team page, and we all understand what does it mean to evaluate an agent.
So I want to have a quick please,
please raise your hand if you know or think you know.
What does it mean to evaluate an agent?
Okay.
Opinions split.
Most people decided not to raise a hand.
That means that my next slide will be super useful, because it's,
actually a definition more formally, evaluation or evaluated,
means that it's a test for your agent system.
A test means input a task like a prompt.
A genetic system, in our case, will be always the agent, like cloud code
or codex or whatever, which takes this prompt at task runs.
It generates a solution.
It might be a file, it might be a full application.
But then on top of it, there is a grading logic,
like verification or test unit tests or rubrics
or alabamas a judge which decides whether it's a good solution or not.
So you get a signal whether your, input was successfully processed
and you get a meaningful result or something.
You know, it doesn't matter.
Well, it's important to, to know
that evals is the core concept of machine learning applications in general.
But no one cares about this before there off the LM,
it was only in the research, environment on the care.
Only the people who, who worked on papers,
but now immediately like Frontier Labs markets, they are new models
based on the results of the evolves, it becomes a hot topic.
And every, every time we see something is released,
big labs main the the benchmarks and evaluations.
And I'm talking right like recent GPT 5.4 when they released the new model,
the first thing which was on their main page was comparison of the new model
with the previous one
against some of the benchmarks where they said, hey, we improve the capabilities.
Again, I'm not drawing.
So that's 4.6.
When it was dropped, they launched like 20.
That's just like, a quick preview of benchmarks showing our new model
is better than our previous generations, but it's also better than other, vendors.
And we've done in previous talk like mentioned that, Google recently
dropped, Android benchmark to specifically assess the capabilities
of how agents perform in their, in, in the Android applications.
So evaluations are driving opinions about how good are the models,
how capable they are.
And sometimes, define whether the people will use the model or not.
But that's a different story.
But the next thing, the next important thing is that.
Okay.
Big labs marketing or,
you know, promote their models through for these, benchmarks.
But like, for me, as a consumer of the model, does it
matter like, does it matter to have a customer?
Well, if I ask you, like, imagine
you had a benchmark specifically for your code base.
Does it resonate with you?
Do does it like, feel like it's something which you would value?
And it's not that time for another quiz.
Like to raise a hand if you think so. Yes or no?
Please respond.
Okay.
Actually, most of the people are convinced that it's true, but I have another slide
to convince even further, depending on what role, you have
in your team, their reason for why you've matter for you
in your day to day might be different.
So imagine you are a software engineer and,
you are maintaining a code base, and you developed a a new context.
I don't know, a Claude Code skill, for example.
How do you know if it's effective?
How do you test it? Right.
So the reason, the only way to do it reliably, without wipes, is
to actually have some reproducible events, like let's go into the next level.
If you're a VP of engineering and you're caring
not about one code base, but about your whole organization,
you want to understand where the agents are failing, right?
To understand like what are the main bottlenecks
and, what are the main like problems with agents?
So you're caring about the whole aggregation.
And the only way to know how to do this is you know, get evals.
even further.
For example, a new Chinese lab,
dropped a super capable open source model, and it's cheaper.
It's faster because it's open source. And you're making the decision.
Do you want to swap, your expensive vendor model, with this or not?
To answer this question, the only way to do it is like, do some reliable tests.
Okay?
Assuming I convince you that you've never, we will continue
with these further.
In the in the talk, the next piece of the talk will be about.
Okay, what are the main building blocks, how to build such evaluation platform.
And the very first building block of it is,
to decide which, school of thought do you accept?
Are you on the going
with the VIP's group who are like, every time new model
is released, every time someone writes something and right, it decides to.
Okay, I will jump to a new solution or you're already into a systematic,
you know, evaluations and studies and monitoring.
So you're ready to invest into,
into,
analyzing how the models perform over the time.
So it's a fundamental question, because if you're in the first team,
then probably it's
okay for short term solutions when you're just like in the developer.
But when you're talking about the organizations and, long term investment
into the agents, it's hard to, to drive your decisions based on on the vibes.
Anyway, people are doing this.
The second thing is to understand the purpose of your eval.
You've also unique because they try to assess specific aspects and you as the
the person who wants to create such evaluation suite needs to understand
what what will be your goal.
Again, it depends on what's your target.
But, I have like a couple of potential goals depending again on the role.
If you're like, then probably you're interested in the degree of automation
and complexity of the features which your agent can do.
And that's why you develop lots of context like skills.
And you want to measure, how good they are.
And, the only input data you need for this is to create this skill
and then have some greenfield environment where you can run your agent,
with access to the skill to solve the problem.
If you're like, want to have a general understanding
of how agent performs in the code base, then probably you want to use the
historical commit data to derive the tasks and see the performance.
By replaying the historical commits, it will give you a high level overview
of how complex features in your code base are, or if you want to.
Again, like monitor the org level, interactions of engineers with agents,
probably you can use the logs and derive the actual
edge cases from the human logs, of how people are interacting.
So now you define.
So the next thing is to actually build the civil,
and building the wall means that you need to have some structure,
some unified format, of your tasks, and how to run them.
The format of the task usually will include at least three things.
One is the, the prompt itself, like what you need to build
the second some Dockerfile environment
where you define some installed dependencies.
And what is available for the agent in the beginning.
And then tests like how to test it, and then you need to wrap it
up to, to be able to run it in a reproducible way.
The Docker containers are usually, the easiest way to do it,
but they're optional.
Cool.
So now you have, goal of the, the benchmark.
Now you have like task, and now you can run the agent against this task.
The core, the key part is to understand how to judge the solutions
and the truth is there is no one single answer.
Instead, there are a couple of options, depending on your like capacity
and the size of your evaluation, you can go with one of three routes.
Usually, one is having a verifiable graders
where you just have unit tests which measure deterministically
whether agent does the work you want to do,
or not through unit tests, through some, you know, like, running
after the execution, something deterministic to verify.
It's fast, cheap, reproducible.
But it's hard to design because it will require you
to manually review a lot of edge cases, and it's hard to scale.
The opposite of this would be to replace
the unit test with other agents or with other models.
So where another reviewer agent will look at your task and try to,
derive whether it's a good solution or not, it's super scalable, right?
Because you can like run thousands of agents in parallel,
and do like lots of other lemmas or judges,
but it of course expensive and it's not non-deterministic.
And another problem, it's like you need calibration.
You need to give a lot of, a lot of context,
a lot of, understanding how to judge the solution.
Otherwise it will just, you know, randomly output.
This is good. This is bad.
And the third approach will be a human graders,
which is infeasible at all for large scales.
But it's, I think, super important in the, in the early stages where in the you're
just prototyping curve, I'll just understand
just to see that your evaluation will do what you want in general
and you're like moving in the right direction.
So for you to eyeball at what happens
and encode your preferences, is, is super essential.
Once you're happy with this, the next step
is to balance between, verifiable graders and model graders.
Cool.
Now, you can, have you have to ask you have agent to run the task.
You have agent to, or whatever to, to solve, and judge.
The next thing is to actually build trust in your course.
And here I have a very interesting anecdotal example.
So it's, running of the terminal bench across
different agents and different models.
And you see at the bottom, the worst performing mini
suite agent, it's at 200 lines, agent, which only has access to read, files,
and write files with Sinatra 4.5, and it has 42.5 percentage.
Score.
But look at the error bars how big they are.
In the most optimistic case, this tiny agent will perform around 50%,
meaning it will match the Codex CLI performance.
Right?
Just because the error bars are so huge, you can't make conclusions.
That means suite agent is worse than a close based solution.
So, trusting your scores, make sure that you're not over optimize into the noise
and that, you you can trust what you see from the metrics call
and just wrap, all components in one feature.
You have Agent Harness, which in this case your cloud code codex
or whatever you have model which you select based on the provider.
You have a collection of those tasks
again, like tasks are prompt, instructions and so on.
You run those tasks, they generate the solutions,
you grade them, they generate scores, and you aggregate them somehow.
And, derive, you know, a feedback based on this.
There are many more
things which we don't cover, just because we don't have time for this.
But again, in practice, there are a lot of, things
which you need to care about, like, updating the evaluation benchmark.
Right?
Because your code base evolves,
that means that your benchmark should evolve as well.
You need to care about how to run it at scale.
You you have 100 tasks.
It's infeasible to run it on your laptop.
It will just die. And. Yeah, like what?
If you want to support more agent and models, and so on, like,
how to how to handle this all, it's it's it's a hard
things, but, we don't cover it here.
And my opinion slash observation is that it's
actually it feels complicated to build, such platform on your own.
And I don't imagine that, like, I can't imagine that any company
will decide to build their own, but at the same time,
there are lots of pain points that can be clustered and addressed in reusable way.
And what we hear from our customers that they are pain points are
usually, clustering can mean in two main cases.
And that's why we built we recently dropped
two evaluation approaches, which I will talk in the next slide.
So the first one is task rivals.
Basically it's
a perfect choice for you if you have standalone context
like for example a cloud code skill or API documentation for a framework.
And you want to understand how agent works with this.
So tasks about tasks evals are perfect for this
because they're just like standalone things.
How it works.
We take your context, we try to analyze it with our,
engine and derive a realistic, realistic scenarios of how this,
context will be used in the real set up.
Those scenarios are like just basically tasks.
And then we run those tasks in two scenarios.
One vanilla agent where agent doesn't have access to this context,
which you created, and another set up where agent has access to this context.
And then we compare this course and see
whether there is an uplift or or instead,
like the scores downgraded or where there is no uplift at all.
If there is an uplift, then of course it means that your context brings
something valuable and agent doesn't know how to do the task without your context.
But if the scores are actually degrading, then probably there is
something controversial and also important for you to look into.
I will show,
the specific, realization of how it looks.
Okay.
I can't do it. I will do it
after after the presentation, because, I mean, the presenter mode.
Yeah. Okay, let's go
to the next slide.
Can I?
Okay.
The next slide is project evals.
So, these this type of evals, is best suitable for you
if you are working with existing codebase and you're shipping the features
inside this code base, for example, your maintainer of the hugging face,
and you want to implement something inside it.
And you just want to understand in general how
agent performs on the tasks specific to this repo.
How would you do this?
Well, project evals is one way to do.
To do so, we analyze the history of the commits, on this, in this repo,
we try to derive those commits which are relevant to your goal.
For example, you're curious about the performance of some specific aspects.
Depending on your setup, you can provide additional context.
And then we also evaluate with context and without basically replaying
those historical commits and seeing what's the performance in general of the agent.
Is it bad then it means like agent on its own probably won't be able to,
solve the problem as it was done by a real, real maintainer.
If the score is a high, that means like the degree
of automation of your, agent is probably good.
So this is a second type of eval.
And, yeah, basically that was the last big thing, which I wanted to say.
We are, jumping into the conclusions, today we covered three main things.
One, the first one is like, why evolves method to date just beyond the,
beyond the Frontier Labs, but for you as well,
because they give you clear guidance how to improve
autonomy, decrease of your agents in your code base even further.
Second is like in case you want to build it from scratch,
what are the main blocks, what to think about?
And third, like how we do it in case you don't want to do it
from scratch, here is like a one click production solution
which is ready for you, which we are building a DSL.
Yeah.
Thank you very much.
Let's stay in touch.
Here is, core code for LinkedIn.
Let's connect.
And yeah, another before we wrap up,
we're hiring your code for the open positions and.
Yeah, also a QR code for the AI native conference, in case you're interested.
Cool. That's it for me.
Thank you very much.
Ready to answer any questions?
Thanks.
I just go back to.
Building skills.
Now I tasks and functions as well.
Yeah. Cool.
Just before we have questions like can I actually quickly, quickly
demo what I wanted to demo.
Because I have the link. Okay.
So the last thing which we dropped was the one of the last thing
which we dropped was this task labels.
So basically what it means you can upload your content,
your skill, and we will generate those synthetic cases.
Here the example was from 11 lab skill.
They have a skill for working with the API for text to speech.
And we doing some like overall review and the quality of the skill.
How impactful the the skill comparing to have no skills are.
Also see that we have landed the security checks but specifically about the evals.
Here you can see those synthetic cases and the performance of the agent
in each scenario with and without having access to, to the context.
So depending on the complexity and uniqueness of your,
we see like here, for example, without context, agent wasn't able
to do anything reasonable at all, depending on the uniqueness
and the complexity of your specific context.
The value of it will be even more because agent doesn't know about this.
But you want to have some, you know, some confirmation that that actually helps.
So, yeah, that's what I wanted to showcase.
Now I'm ready to answer questions.
Thank you for thinking that all of the,
Eagles, all the rubrics and everything are all in there as well.
So it's not just you know, zeros and hundreds.
The all the text that describes.
Yeah I see that there as well.
I think you score on the right hand side as a tree view with the Eagles.
I thank my yeah. Cook.
Yeah. You can read.
Thank you.
When you see a, model grade, is it important
to use a different model from the one that, originally generated the page?
Yeah.
So it's a very good question because there are lots of biases.
Right?
So if you're doing them where there's a judge like,
with a model which solves the problem and then the, the same model grades it
like different agent, but, same model by nature.
There will be biases.
The, the, the different ways how to handle it.
What we saw that
anthropic models are less biased, less biased comparing to others.
So it's more of a concern to, to other models beyond the anthropic one.
But basically you can shuffle, you can try to again, like
take the frontier model of one provider and generate the specific aspects
with this model, to, to make it unbiased.
So yeah, like there are no silver bullet for this.
You always have trade offs.
But yeah, that's a risks.
That's why you ideally want to combine two both signals.
One is the signal from the verifiable,
I don't like running unit tests and running some deterministic checks
and also like alarms a judge, because alarms, a judge will usually
give you more nuanced insights.
And if you can provide additional feedback
into the LMS, a judge, the verifiable feedback.
Right.
So like results of how the tests were running,
then you are reducing this bias as well because it will pay attention to them.
To, to to the results of running the tests rather than making
its own decisions.
So like lots of ways how to deal with this bias.
Thank you. Cool.
And I think, thank you.
Question, evolves on our grade, but they're just giving you
a snapshot of what is currently happening.
So my question is, have you played with any optimizer
like G and or anything like that?
I know that it's more, let's say, focus on text.
Something.
But yeah. So
yeah. Absolutely.
Like even
just like capturing what you have in your code base at the current, shape.
That's why one of the big problems with evolve and challenges
is to build, a pipeline where you can evolve in time.
So your, your evolves, evolve with your code base,
but also like you need to have this optimized mechanism
ideally, blocked into your pipeline as well.
So we are testing like or for not only the evolution but also like optimized loop.
So based on the feedback from you also generate some recommendations.
But what can you do.
How can you improve your context, to reduce the errors.
So the short answer is like, yeah, we're playing with our own optimizers.
We didn't use like external solutions,
because we're developing like our for, for loop ourselves.
Sorry.
Yeah.
Thank you. Thank you very much. Rex.
I just wanted to, quickly ask,
you see, all these evolves, but I think what you have was basically,
the this spinning combination of getting the skill to got the code base.
Using, as you mentioned, like using like block entities.
If you containerize these engines, are you using something like the Claude's
agents SDK under the hood to like, this all together in the training
calling cloud code by the client pop up telling it to to go do something.
Yeah.
So basically, we're, we're using agents in autonomous mode, right?
So they are, we're spinning them up in the isolated environment
where everything's prepared.
It's like, not risky to if if they crash something.
And we're like, we're mixing basically like,
they're like different agents pre-installed with those different modes
and depending on them, a specific aspect we are like can use the SDK.
For example, when we want to
track the activation rates, we actually want to stop early.
If we realized that the agent decided not to pick up a skill and we can
we can derive this information from the SDK because SDK,
you know, you can you can control everything.
What happens and terminate the process if you realize that the agent doesn't,
pick up the skill.
So, yeah, we are like, combining, all the things.
It's just going to ask,
with, like, model gradients,
when you run a lot of model based emails, it feels like it gets pretty expensive.
Exactly.
I want to know if you have any, like, treats for the same thing or cost I guess.
Yeah. So,
during the
like prototyping phase when we're like prototyping
how we would look like we're not caring about cost reductions at all.
We want to do as many experiments as we can,
with additional agent reviewers on top of the evals
to distill those, you know, runs into some meaningful, bar plot.
So during R&D phase, we don't care during the,
that, like, when we ship it to the customer, we have cash.
Basically, we don't run out if something if the code base didn't change.
Right.
So you only rerun scenarios which are probably affected by the code,
by the changes in the code base or like the feature commit or whatever.
So, yeah, like, mainly we try to avoid
regenerating what doesn't change, what doesn't happen.
You know, like what doesn't touch the previously, in the integrated context.
But yeah, it's very expensive.
That's that's totally true.
That's why it's so, compelling
to switch to open source model, rather than pay vendors.
So, yeah.
Cool.
I have a question about translating science agents.
So the very open ended agents that can solve,
you know, problems we don't know the solution for,
so I have, you know, multiple agents,
and I want to compare them only at solving this science problem.
So it's an open ended one that I don't really have a verifiable.
Yeah.
So I need to use it as a judge of problems that.
Yeah, it's clear to use because I don't know the answer myself.
Exactly.
I get trajectories from two agents of many
thousands of tokens.
Yeah, I, I don't even know what you know.
How would you go about like, what criteria exactly?
It's an amazing question I don't have like, well, I swear to you,
because, like, if we don't know, like, what's the actual
what should be the ideal response, then I think there is a combination of us
looking into the problem
and like trying to analyze the, I don't know, like the formula which
the science agent figured out and trying to, see
if it resonates with our feelings and how it should, how it should work,
or like, spinning in parallel, like lots of additional agent reviewers,
which we biased towards some, some preference, which we have, like,
because we ideally want observe some pattern.
Right.
And probably, we prompt the new reviewer agents with this specific goal.
It will be able to handle this, or at least, reduce this search space
for us, as a humans, in terms of, like what to validate,
that's one piece of, how to respond to this.
The second, part of the response would be probably there is still a way
to introduce, checkpoints or milestones into the trajectories.
So you, can validate that the least agent
did something which you expected it for me to do, like some,
I don't know, so that the solution didn't diverge completely.
Right.
So it's not nonsense, but it's something which follows your intuition.
And you can like you can you can encode those preferences for sure.
Not completely, but at least like, again, reduce
the search space, and filter out very bad solutions.
Yeah.
That's, my, my only like, if I were to do something like this, I
would do it this way.
Cool.
And then is,
I was interested in, stories and, because,
it's important
for what is going on now in the program.
Yeah.
What do you explain the sums or maybe proportion?
Between, expenses, tokens and expenses, conference,
expenses on what?
Expenses?
Expenses on tokens and expenses on federal.
Okay.
Yeah,
yeah.
And, yeah.
So what are the what's the proportion of.
It's like one one, 210 or maybe 121.
What is going on.
I think it's worth you.
Yeah.
I think like economics is for, for us it's, it's a big journey to understand
what's the, how the economics how to make the economics work.
One way to think about this is that, like every evaluation
will be unique depending on what benchmark you have, like what
code base you have and what complexity of the task you're dealing with.
For example, if you're working with UI applications,
then testing UI applications is actually more expensive
because agent would spend a lot of effort to spin up the application, then
introduce some visual vision model to, you know, review that,
it does something meaningful.
So it will be more expensive if it's like simple, like algorithmic challenges, then
probably they will be off on a different, you know, like scale, of course.
But so far, my experience was that,
like, on average, the task will be roughly beyond 2
or $3 per task, for, for an agent to, to run and solve it.
And beyond $1 to grade the solution.
So based on this, you can probably and these are the numbers with frontier
models.
Based on this, probably can calculate how much it will cost you to run it
1000 times, 21 days a month,
in case you were
to do something new every, every, every day.
But yeah, like, that's that's so far
my my answer.
Is it's more like
5050 all tokens
takes more than a barrel.
So. So,
I think it's a, I
think I was, yeah,
I, yeah, I understand the question.
I think it's a number. I don't think it's something.
Yeah, yeah.
Cool.
Any more questions for us from the public?
I don't stop to
to do the, He hasn't done anything interesting.
So, you know, we.
Why he takes questions, and it's,
it also fits into the SDLC.
So I think that would be good to see.
So to do you think it's a if I asked him too much in my code base,
with on my team is that
that is the same thing like where I, I like to to push engineers
to, to understand some coverage, from, according to your providers.
Like, how was I talking, in an engineering chain?
So the
question is like, how would you combine,
like engineers with, engineers with results of agents work
or maybe I.
Yeah.
So basically, what I heard recently from one of our design partners
that they integrated the evolution in the CI CD pipeline.
So whenever they ship some skill, they automatically trigger
our eval to just validate the, the skill, bring something.
Right.
So like a, like a task eval for example, doesn't obviously, degrade
and they don't observe like obvious like failures.
That's one story, one anecdote I heard.
Another would be
which this the set up which we currently, prototyping
is collaborative, development where engineer is still in the loop
and an engineer is guiding what the task will be and reviewing,
what the agent decided to implement and verifies
whether they like, you know, the outcome of intermediate steps.
And basically engineers are,
like in the, in the chat mode decided,
discussing with them, and with an agent who works on task.
Well, some aspects like, do I like it, does it capture enough information?
Do I like the unit tests?
So it's basically becomes a combination where you, as the engineer
don't write anymore, but you just validate that it doesn't
that, it doesn't, you know, like, diverge,
the agent doesn't diverge and doesn't come up with a sophisticated,
contrived task, but rather something really sticks.
So you are in the loop to help to create a real scenario without writing any code.
You just monitor that?
It does something reasonable, because sometimes just a couple of
corrections is enough to help it to go from the dead loop, basically.
Wonderful.
Thank you very much for your questions. And thanks, Max.
Fantastic talk at number 15.